Now we'll call it over the regular scheduled meeting for the Modesty Council for Monday, June 6th, 2022.
Public hearing on the proposed fiscal year 2022-23 budget, note this public hearing is called.
For any member of the public to present to the gathering body, comments, recommendations or information on any part of the proposed budget.
And we're going to move on to three. Proclamation declaring, go do I got close up, but meeting your in there.
Certainly, you can do that, maybe.
This is one off I had to.
There's no public, there's no public comment.
Okay, three proclamation declaring, June 7th, 2022 as State Farm Day.
State Farm is celebrating 100 years.
So, Nate Long from down at the State Farm here in town called and talked to me about it.
So we got a proclamation for them.
He couldn't be here tonight, he's out town, so let's present to him a letter date.
But tomorrow's going to be State Farm Day, man.
As long as we approve that, I guess.
Do we have to approve it here?
Yes.
I'll show you.
Second.
All right.
Thank you.
Four.
Public input.
We're on schedule personal chances.
We have Mr. Beckard Jim.
The Association ranks to your endangered movement.
I'm really sorry to say that we made that with a sign even from the tan.
It means that we're endangered.
Lots of times endangered things.
We have the heavy metals coming down.
Dr. Dickie, every day.
And what we're asking you in the public to do is to ask the agencies that have some jurisdictions,
some power to actually do a member of the African-American and to come together and work together
on the whole issue.
I'm so we're asking EPA from FEMA and she are going to sit down.
Consider the whole issue because what happens at Tarkree doesn't stay you. It stains us and it stains on
But it ends up ingrained like an against a beneficity
And it also ends up in the drinking
In two halves all around
So I have some handouts for you
From the mirror, we're going to consider
At some point, I'd like you to consider a resolution to do as these agencies
For example, to work together
I also have some sample letters
Anyone should want to write a letter
You can do that
It's like there's always some samples for you
I want to thank you very much for installing this sign
I really do
I'm sorry, I had a few in place
Put it more permanently
But there is some other areas that raised a sign
To try to preserve the children
And so, they must not have come by the Sunday, or surely they will know.
And a very technical day, PQ is said, I believe, mayors to think six thousand residents here.
Or in the children's yard to pray on our school in January.
And I wouldn't forget, because I too believe that it is.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Five consent consent agenda.
Staff recommends we approve six and seven.
Second.
Local.
Davis.
Hi.
7 birth.
Eight.
Budget amendment.
22-27 Main Street.
MSUA Airport.
General administration, wastewater collection.
Closing out of funds, receipt, and expand grant funds, receipt, and expand the Oklahoma Water Resource Support.
Job.
No, no.
You're not.
These are on vacations.
Poor part.
This first amendment is a four-part amendment.
We're closing the Main Street grant fund.
It literally has a penny in it.
So we want to move that to the position.
The police department is receding and extending $6600.
It was a reimbursement for education from the PQA to try.
Here.
report fund is receiving and extending some FAA grant monies and then wastewater collection
is receiving and extending a reimbursement of the RELIN.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Parker?
Aye.
The report.
Davis?
Aye.
Sumber?
I understand.
By the name of 22-28, MDRA, facility is calling them $3.50 from the general fund to the
MDRA fund, based on the Coleman, it's for elevator maintenance.
We don't have that one up here anyway.
No, it should be in the back.
So, okay.
Aye.
Sumber?
Davis?
Aye.
Parker?
10.
Fiscal Year 22-23 municipal budget message and resolution regarding the city of Myama, Oklahoma budget.
So, fiscal year 22-23, establishing budget amendment authority.
So, mayor members of the council, as you just noted in your
package, you have a copy of the fiscal year 22-23 fiscal year budget for the general fund.
In this case, since we've already talked about the M.S.U.A. this part is just the general fund.
As you all know, this has been a topic of several ongoing team meetings and discussions, including
Myama City Council.
mayor and city staff. We began the budget process this year evaluating a five-year averages
to help calculate the appropriate revenues and expenses. I'd like to state for the council
in citizens what is being presented today is a balanced budget. Regarding the general fund over
all projected revenues total $20 million, $100,946. And the projected expenditures total $20,064,321.
This includes transfers in totaling $8,82,192. Although we finished the fiscal year really
strong, there were many revenue discussions with staff in council, whether this level of sales
and use tax revenue income is an anomaly or sustainable. There are many volatile factors of
course that influence the tax revenue growth, such as COVID related spending, medical marijuana
revenues, and federal relief spending, which are very all very unpredictable in the coming
fiscal year. The good news is we have many levers that we can pull on throughout the year. This
next fiscal year and the event we see signs of a significant downturn in the economy
or recession. And let me assure everyone we will be watching the numbers very closely and we won't
hesitate to bring the council in a minute budget if needed. That being said, the council's direction
was pretty clear and that was this is the time to bet on ourselves. And so with this in mind, we
are making changes related to sports tourism and CBBE to further support making my Emma a destination
for entertainment and tourism. These are pretty significant changes. Additionally, we are putting a
primary focus on employee retention and recruitment this next fiscal year. Over this past year,
we have certainly struggled as many have with around 10% in overall job vacancy. This has been
really tough on employees in on morale. To say the least, we are currently contracting with a third
party to perform a salary study, which will be evaluating to apply a market adjustment across the
organization for wages. In addition to personnel, other expenses discussed include $443,141
in materials and $1,949,471 in other services and charges. In transfers of $8,494,295 for the overall
project, a total expense budget of $20,064,321. As I mentioned earlier, capital improvement
plans requested for this general fund came in at $2,295.
$354 of which we paired down and prioritized to fit budget now at $669,178.
Infosys was placed on life safety issues as a top priority.
Finally, one of the primary requests by the Council was that there would be a focus on streets.
The budget before you represents $3,241,018 in street repair and replacement, thanks to one time
ARPA funding.
There have been no material changes from the last time that the Council met on April 25th to review
and discuss the preliminary budget.
And I'd be happy to answer any questions you all might have.
And one that line item or it says establishing budget and minimum authority, can you explain that to us please?
Oh yeah.
Trying to figure out if you're talking to me or been.
Okay, me and I.
So what that gives is gives the city manager authority to transfer money inside of a fund.
So inside the general fund, you can transfer money from one department to another, one line item to another,
inside the same department.
And you can't transfer money from fund to fund.
Like, emission rate of fund.
You couldn't do that.
That would be a budget and minimum.
And as you know, we do that often.
As need be, we have additional funds in one area, but we've decided we want to move them.
And that's when we'll come to you and you'll see like you saw the budget and then it's earlier.
That will come to the Council to do those budget and minimum.
That process will remain.
So nothing will change.
So if that process will change, those appointed putting that in there on the line item.
I think it's standard language that's in there.
It's in the authority to actually move money like I'm going to say pd and fired in this last year.
Pd and fire or if the parks has money, he's moved to facilities.
He has the authority to do that.
So if the budget says we're going to spend this much money, he can't change that.
But he can move all this money inside.
Just move it around inside that front.
Because that happens all day.
The need to move.
The need to reconcile it with these.
If we do, do ladies.
Yes.
It'll be a budget and then.
Or if we want to move money from one fund to another,
MSUA to.
Or rainy day.
We want to move rainy day to purchase something in the capital agreement.
That's in the council.
So in this case, even my capital improvement is a separate from the general fund.
So if we were going to move money from capital improvements to the general fund,
for some of the purpose, we'd have to come to the council.
Rainy day as well.
It's a separate fund.
You know what I'm about.
Good night.
So this time next year, 6.30 of 23, for estimating it's going to be 5.499.798, there'll be some interest in there, but we don't budget the interest, based on 5.5 million.
Yeah, the question is, should I do it on the budget?
I'll second.
Davis?
All right.
Parker?
Zimmer?
Hi.
I'm just standing again.
11, engagement letter, but the Audres and Associates for Audres Services to conduct the fiscal year 2122 audit.
If it's the last time, we need, we have to engage an auditor within 30 days of the end of the fiscal year.
Last year, this time, we went out for an RFP for a three year RFP.
This is the second of the third year.
Arlington is the one we've recommended and you agree with.
So we're asking you to approve the second of three years with Arlington.
They will audit this fiscal year 2021.
I will tell you, I've been very impressed with Arlington.
This is actually a group I was not familiar with.
As I have been with some of our other third party fiscal firms.
But I've been very impressed with him and have even learned that the state Department of Accounting uses the same folks when they have special audits that they want to do it.
The state level.
Arlington Associates is who they utilize.
And I can see why.
They've been very professional.
Very available in very knowledge.
Nick Nelson to approve.
Sand.
Sandberg.
Double.
Davis.
All right.
Twelve.
Renewal contract between the Ottawa County and the City of Miami to provide dispatch.
services to audible county.
Back in November, we started dispatching countywide
through the MIMO Police Department.
At that time, I'm on a county providing funding for two
dispatchers that existed contract carriers through the
fiscal year.
So this is just an extension of our agreement where we're
building now.
The price would go up about $5,000 or $88.
Now that's just reflects Mary's and
parades for our dispatchers.
So they're still providing two dispatchers
to work.
I see my employees in our dispatch center and we provide
the kind of way to dispatch services.
This is just going to the next last week.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Thank you.
Parker.
Hi.
Senator.
Davis.
Don't go.
Thanks, Chief.
13 procedures for the upcoming town hall
public meeting are going flood issues.
So you have at your respective seats.
A proposal that I've worked on had David helped me with the
IT parts of it and Melissa helped me from their
perspective.
This is to modify our procedures that we have in place for
public speaking at a council meeting because the very nature of
this proposed meeting will be significantly different than
what we normally do.
One of the main points of that whole meeting will be to
hear from the public.
And so this is the proposal that we have put together.
There are two parts of it that are highlighted for you.
Just wanted to make sure that we have this the way that you
want it.
Obviously we can change anything else that is in here.
But the two things that were the most significant after
we discussed all of this and how it's actually going to work is
whether they speakers are going to be limited to three minutes.
And then if they are limited, whatever their limited is is if they
say something that may cause a response from either the council
members or one of the other speakers that is at the meeting.
Does that time count against them?
As part of their, there are a lot of amount of time to speak.
We would submit that it should simply because otherwise it
make it.
almost impossible for, for instance, for David to be turning off and on the timer and somebody's going to think it got started too early or
waited too long for somebody else and not them and on and on. So, so those are the major questions that we wanted to make sure that you all are satisfied with.
But obviously, anything else in here is certainly something that we can change if you don't like.
You don't like some aspect of it. It is a significant deviation from what our normal routine council meetings policy or procedure is.
So are the speakers that are coming there to address however many of the systems. They're limited to three minutes.
Not not the agenda speakers. The public, we will have the agenda speakers give their spills. We have some timelines that we're really trying to hold them to.
But a main part of the whole meeting is to hear from the public.
We hope that there's a lot of people there. We don't. The reason we ultimately said on the three minutes first of all that's what we thought you told us.
But second of all, we want to make sure that everybody that wants to talk gets the opportunity to do that.
And we can't have somebody taking up the amount of time that's allocated for everybody just being used up by one person or a few people.
It does allow them to just say what they want to say. If that's all they're wanting to do, it does allow them to ask a question.
But they only get one question. At the end of that, they can go back to the back of the line and work their way through again.
And again, that's what we were understanding was what you all thought would be the best way to handle that.
And again, the people are anticipating.
There's five agenda. And the mayor will be starting the meeting as a regular council meeting so that you all can vote on these modifications to the rules.
Then we're going to have five speakers in there.
Three of those speakers will be the mayor and two past mayors, which have a short time.
A lot of the other two are attorneys that have presentations that they're going to be giving in the night.
I've got a five-minute intro in there, I think, and I'm going to do probably right after
a blast.
It calls the meeting orders, that's the rules, and then I'll do a welcome and kind of talk
the public through the agenda, do introductions, and then turn it over to our first speaker.
The idea is that we can get through it right now, I think, we can get through most of the
presentations within the first hour, and that leaves us an entire hour for Q&A.
That's 20 people.
These things are perfect.
We're a faster one.
The third and line.
Sure.
They get to ask question.
So we may be the second.
Any instruments is responsible if you got 20 people to offer your line.
That says I'm here in nine o'clock.
The third and line.
That's the right one.
It's the right one.
That's the more we can get line.
But the third and line in the Q, they get to ask our station, that's the question.
So we may be the kind of person who was lying.
And we may give the audience an opportunity if they want to leave the can.
So we're not holding anybody hostage.
Certainly.
But everybody that we've talked to that's coming to present or answer questions is willing to stay as needed.
So you want to ask about on this tonight.
We would like to because number one we want to, if it is what you all are improving, we want to
send it to the other speakers so that they'll be aware of that.
And we also want to get it out to the public so that the public will be aware of it.
You know, we talked about if they want to bring something for you to see.
We address it.
We address it one way if it's something as simple as a piece of paper or a photograph.
But we have to have to deal with it differently if it's something that's going to be loaded onto our computers.
We don't want to infect our computers on and on.
So in order for the public to be aware of this, we want to get it out as soon as possible.
How much emotion to prove?
Don't call.
All right.
Davis.
Somewhere.
Just mayor all eliminate these highlights and they have a finished product, but so are you in agreement by that motion that we are
Once they start they got three minutes
Right, okay, I think that's right. It's a little bit of my thanks. Yes, so I'll add that
Finished for you so you can sign it tonight definitely we can get it out
All right 14 other new business of any which is a residence of the posting of this agenda
15 staff reports
16 mayor counsel community announcements
Since I ripped on them last year
I'm gonna brag on them this year
Cemetery folks
Got the grass mode this year despite the monsoon
And got to give credit where credit is due it looked really nice. I have a couple here
Young lady that goes to my post schools
Loss of this last name called like our first name, but she came up that idea about the door lots
for the schools and
There's a great effort and
Every door we got covered and this was a
Elementary school student is that correct. They came with this idea and
I thought it was pretty
Entrepreneur rule of her to do start that project and see it through
And I
Holland that's it Holland Losson and so I want to mention her
Like I may just have to it next time
Hmm
All right, 17
This means we'll be continued from the council chambers reconvene the staff room the purpose of executive session
I think the police have the gender in gender out of 15 of the rigor
He probably is discussing executive session under contract
17, or 18, adjournment.
So I'll move.
Doke?
Five.
Davis?
Cender?
Hi.
Parker.
Now, we can be in the council and the child for chambers of the regular city council
meeting and action on the matters of dressing executive session, which would be the contracts
of Chuck.
I'm going to like a last line here.
Just in the, as written, and Bo Reese, and Ben Loring, as amended.
Motion.
Second.
Hi.
Davis?
Parker.
All right.
21.
Cender.
Davis.
Parker.
21.
Cender.
22.
Drummond.
So moved.
Thank you.
Simple.
Five.
Davis.
Cender.